Guide to the Thomas Parran Papers, 1892-1968 UA.90.F14
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Dr. Parran (University of Pittsburgh) A-Z, 1948-1961; XIX.
  - American Academy of Pediatrics (Box 80, Folder 1164)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science (Box 80, Folder 1165)
  - American Assembly, "The Federal Government and Higher Education", May 1960 (Box 80, Folder 1166)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 81, Folder 1167)
  - American Bakers Association American Institute of Baking Dinner, February 27, 1961 (Box 81, Folder 1168)
  - American Board of Preventive Medicine (Box 81, Folder 1169)
  - American Cancer Society (Box 81, Folder 1170)
  - American College of Dentists (Box 81, Folder 1171)
  - American College of Hospital Administrators (Box 81, Folder 1172)
  - American College of Physicians (Box 81, Folder 1173)
  - American College of Surgeons (Box 81, Folder 1174)
  - American Hospital Association (Box 81, Folder 1175)
  - American Medical Association (Box 81, Folder 1176)
  - American Museum of Health (Box 81, Folder 1177)
  - American Pharmaceutical Association (Box 81, Folder 1178)
  - American Psychiatric Association (Box 81, Folder 1179)
  - American Public Health Assn. "Rich Report" (Box 81, Folder 1180)
  - American Social Health Association (Box 82, Folder 1181)
  - American Social Hygiene Assn. (Box 82, Folder 1182)
  - American Social Hygiene Assn., 1948-50 (Box 82, Folder 1183)
  - American Statistical Assn. (Box 82, Folder 1184)
  - Antiques (Box 82, Folder 1185)
  - Arnstein, Mr. Lawrence (Box 82, Folder 1186)
  - Arthritis Rheumatism Foundation (Box 82, Folder 1187)
  - Assn. of American Medical Colleges (Box 82, Folder 1188)
  - Assn. of American Medical Colleges Annual Meeting (Chicago), November 2-4, 1959 (Box 82, Folder 1190)
  - Assn. of American Medical Colleges. Medical School Teaching Hospital Section - Meeting, 10/30-31/1959. (Box 82, Folder 1191)
  - Assn. of American Physicians (Box 82, Folder 1192)
  - Assn. of Food and Drug Officials of the United States (Box 82, Folder 1193)
  - Assn. of Schools of Public Health Meeting, April 11 (Box 82, Folder 1194)
  - B - miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 1195)
  - Bacon, Mr. Emery F. (Box 83, Folder 1196)
  - Baehr, Dr. George (Box 83, Folder 1197)
  - Baumgartner, Dr. Leona (Box 83, Folder 1198)
  - Bayne-Jones, Dr. Stanhope (Box 83, Folder 1199)
  - Blatt, Mrs. Betty (Box 83, Folder 1200)
  - Blunt, Miss Virginia H. (Box 83, Folder 1201)
  - Braceland, Dr. Francis J. (Box 83, Folder 1202)
  - Brotherston, Dr. John H.F. (Box 83, Folder 1203)
  - Broughton, Mr. Philip S. (Box 83, Folder 1204-1205)
  - Burney, Dr. Leroy E. (Box 83, Folder 1206)
  - C - miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 1207)
  - California, University of (includes re. Honorary Degree, 1958) (Box 84, Folder 1208)
  - Calvert County Historical Society (Maryland) (Box 84, Folder 1209)
  - Central Blood Bank of Pittsburgh (Box 84, Folder 1210)
  - Ciocco, Dr. Antonio (Box 84, Folder 1211)
  - Citizens' Committee for the Settlements (United Neighborhood Houses) (Box 84, Folder 1212)
  - Collier's, Must You Retire at 65? (Box 84, Folder 1213)
  - Columbia University, First Bicentennial Conference, 1954 (Box 84, Folder 1214)
  - Columbia University, Graduate School of Journalism, Advisory Committee (Box 84, Folder 1215)
  - Committee on Govt. Operations, United States Senate (Box 84, Folder 1216)
  - Committee to Protect Our Children's Teeth, Inc. (Box 84, Folder 1217)
  - Community Rehabilitation Center (Box 84, Folder 1218)
  - Copenhagen, Denmark, August-Sept. 1957 (Box 84, Folder 1219)
  - Cosmos Club (Box 84, Folder 1220)
  - D - Miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 1221)
  - Daley, Sir Allen (Box 85, Folder 1222)
  - Darwin Centennial Celebration. Univ. of Chicago, November 24-28, 1959 (Box 85, Folder 1223)
  - De Kruif, Paul (Box 85, Folder 1224)
  - Denver Conference. Re: Tuberculosis, (Jan. 1957) (Box 85, Folder 1225)
  - de Paula Souza, Dr, Raphael (Box 85, Folder 1226)
  - Dubos, Dr. Rene (Box 85, Folder 1227)
  - Duquesne Club (Box 85, Folder 1228)
  - E - Miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 1229)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 85, Folder 1230)
  - Engineering Centennial, 1952 (Box 85, Folder 1231)
  - F - Miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 1232)
  - Falk, Mr. Leon (Box 85, Folder 1233)
  - Falk, Dr. Leslie A. (Box 85, Folder 1234)
  - Fisher Scientific Company (Box 85, Folder 1235)
  - Folks, Homer (Box 86, Folder 1236)
  - Food Law Institute, Inc. (Box 86, Folder 1237)
  - Forand Bill (Box 86, Folder 1238)
  - Foreign Policy Association of Pittsburgh (Box 86, Folder 1239)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. (Box 86, Folder 1240)
  - Fox, Dr. T.F. (Box 86, Folder 1241)
  - Freeman, Dr. Victor J. (Box 86, Folder 1242)
  - Fuid Health Foundation, Helene (Box 86, Folder 1243)
  - Frontier Nursing Service (Box 86, Folder 1244)
  - G - Miscellaneous (Box 86, Folder 1245)
  - Georgetown University (Box 86, Folder 1246)
  - Grant, Dr. John Bo (Box 86, Folder 1247)
  - Gregg, Dr. Alan re: Alan Gregg Fund (Box 86, Folder 1248)
  - H - Miscellaneous (Box 86, Folder 1249)
  - Harvard University, Board of Overseers of Harvard College (Box 86, Folder 1250)
  - Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York (Box 87, Folder 1251)
  - Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York Health and Medical Care in New York City (Box 87, Folder 1252)
  - Helsinki, Finland, visit, August-Sept. 1957 (Box 87, Folder 1253)
  - Heritage Series - Station WQED (Box 87, Folder 1254)
  - Hershenson, Dr. Lee M. (Box 87, Folder 1255)
  - Herzog, Dr. Carl J. (Box 87, Folder 1256)
  - Hilleboe, Dr. Herman E. (Box 87, Folder 1257)
  - Hingson, Dr. Robert A. (Box 87, Folder 1258)
  - Hospital Planning Association of Allegheny County. (Box 87, Folder 1259)
  - I - Miscellaneous (Box 87, Folder 1260)
  - Institute of International Education. Seminar on Soviet Education, Nov. 19-20, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 1261)
  - International Health and Medical Research Act of 1959. (Hill-Fogarty Bill) (Box 87, Folder 1262)
  - J - Miscellaneous (Box 87, Folder 1263)
  - Jones, Mr. Boisfeuillet. Comm. of Consultants on Medical Res. Rept. to Senate Apps. Comm. (Box 87, Folder 1264)
  - K - Miscellaneous (Box 87, Folder 1265)
  - Knickerbocker Club, Inc. (Box 87, Folder 1266)
  - L - Miscellaneous (Box 87, Folder 1267)
  - Leonard Wood Memorial (Box 88, Folder 1268)
  - Lima, Peru, 1950 (Box 88, Folder 1269)
  - Lima, Peru Pan American Sanitary Bureau, 1949 (Box 88, Folder 1270)
  - London visit, Sept. 1957 (Box 88, Folder 1271)
  - Longenecker, Dr. Herbert E. (Box 88, Folder 1272)
  - Lorentz, Mr. Pare (Box 88, Folder 1273)
  - Mc - Miscellaneous (Box 88, Folder 1274)
  - M - Miscellaneous (Box 88, Folder 1275)
  - Mackintosh, Dr. James M., 1959 (Box 88, Folder 1276)
  - Mackintosh, Dr. James M., 1957-1958 (Box 88, Folder 1277)
  - Milwaukee Journal, News Clippings, June 12, 1950 (Box 88, Folder 1,277A)
  - Maryland Historical Society (Box 89, Folder 1278)
  - Maryland Self-Survey Commission re: Baltimore meeting, December 9-10 1957 (Box 89, Folder 1279)
  - Maryland State Planning Commission. Report of Subcommittee on Medical Education and Research. (Box 89, Folder 1280)
  - Medical Care Literature (Box 89, Folder 1281)
  - Mellon, Mr. Paul (Box 89, Folder 1282)
  - Mellon, Mrs. Paul (Box 89, Folder 1283)
  - Mexico, July 12-Aug. 15, 1951 (Box 89, Folder 1284)
  - Mexico, Aug. 23-Sept. 10, 1949 (Box 89, Folder 1285)
  - Meyer, Mrs. Eugene (Box 89, Folder 1286)
  - Mirsky, Dr. I. Arthur (Box 89, Folder 1287)
  - Montefiore Hospital (New York) (Dr. George A. Silver) (Box 89, Folder 1288)
  - Moore, Dr. Jospeh Earle (and Mrs.) (Box 89, Folder 1289)
  - Mountain Memorial (Jospeh W.) (Box 89, Folder 1290)
  - Mutual of Omaha - CRISS Award presentation, Nov. 1959 (Box 89, Folder 1291)
  - N - Miscellaneous (Box 90, Folder 1292)
  - National Academy of Sciences Comm. on Loyalty (Report of) (Box 90, Folder 1293)
  - National Association of Science Writers (Box 90, Folder 1294)
  - National Cancer Institute (Box 90, Folder 1295)
  - National Council on Community Foundations (Box 90, Folder 1296)
  - National Health Council (Box 90, Folder 1297)
  - National Health Council meeting Comm. on Research, January 19, 1960 (Box 90, Folder 1298)
  - National Health Council. National Advisory Committee on Local Health Departments (Box 90, Folder 1299)
  - National Institutes of Health (Box 90, Folder 1300)
  - National Jewish Hospital at Denver (Box 90, Folder 1301)
  - National League for Nursing (Box 90, Folder 1302)
  - National Planning Association (Box 90, Folder 1303)
  - New York City Miscellaneous (Box 90, Folder 1304)
  - New York City Commission on Health Services (Box 90, Folder 1305)
  - New York City. Dept. of Health (Box 90, Folder 1306)
  - New York City. Dept. of Health. Study of Patterns of Medical Care (Box 90, Folder 1307)
  - New York State. Committee on Medical Education - Expenses (Box 90, Folder 1308)
  - Old Dominion Foundation (Box 90, Folder 1309)
  - Operation Serenity (Lancet) (Box 91, Folder 1310)
  - Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission (Laurence S. Rockefeller) (Box 91, Folder 1311)
  - O - Miscellaneous (Box 91, Folder 1312)
  - P - Miscellaneous (Box 91, Folder 1313)
  - Pate, Mr. Maurice (Box 91, Folder 1314)
  - Pennsylvania Health Council (Box 91, Folder 1315)
  - Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Association (Box 91, Folder 1316)
  - The Pharos. Alpha Omega Alpha Honor Medical Society (Box 91, Folder 1317)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America (Box 91, Folder 1318)
  - Psychiatry - Information in re. (Box 91, Folder 1319)
  - R - Miscellaneous (Box 91, Folder 1320)
  - Radiation (reference articles) (Box 91, Folder 1321)
  - Rappleye, Dr Willard C. (Box 91, Folder 1322)
  - Rhodes Bill - H.R. 6871 (Box 91, Folder 1323)
  - Robertson, Dr. Alexander (Univ. of Saskatchewan) (Box 91, Folder 1324)
  - Rockefeller Institute, The (Box 92, Folder 1325)
  - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1958-1961 (Box 92, Folder 1326)
  - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1957 (Box 92, Folder 1327)
  - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1952-1956 (Box 92, Folder 1328)
  - Rolling Rock Club (Box 92, Folder 1329)
  - Roosevelt, Mrs. Franklin D. (Box 92, Folder 1330)
  - Roosevelt University (Chicago) (Box 92, Folder 1331)
  - Rusk, Dr. Howard A. (Box 92, Folder 1332)
  - S - Miscellaneous (Box 92, Folder 1333)
  - Robertson, Dr. Alexander (Univ. of Saskatchewan) (Box 92, Folder 1334)
  - Salk, Dr. Jonas E. (Box 93, Folder 1335)
  - Schmidt, A.W. (Box 93, Folder 1336)
  - Shepard, Dr. William P. (Box 93, Folder 1337)
  - Sissman, Dr. Isaac. (Box 93, Folder 1338)
  - Smith, Dr. Charles E. (Box 93, Folder 1339)
  - Social Medicine (Box 93, Folder 1340-1341)
  - Society for International Development (Box 93, Folder 1342)
  - Spies, Dr. Tom D. (Box 93, Folder 1343)
  - State Charities Aid Association (Box 93, Folder 1344)
  - State University of New York (Box 93, Folder 1345)
  - Stockholm, Sweden visit, Aug.-Sept. 1957 (Box 93, Folder 1346)
  - Stryker, Roy (Box 93, Folder 1347)
  - Tuberculosis (Box 93, Folder 1348)
  - T - Miscellaneous (Box 93, Folder 1349)
  - U - Miscellaneous (Box 93, Folder 1350)
  - United Fund of Allegheny County (Box 93, Folder 1351)
  - United Fund of Allegheny County- Applications for Grant-in-Aid (Box 94, Folder 1352)
  - United Fund of Allegheny County- I. Cancer (Box 94, Folder 1353)
  - United Fund of Allegheny County- II. Heart (Box 94, Folder 1354)
  - United Fund of Allegheny County- III. Heart, Cancer Muscular Dystrophy (Box 94, Folder 1355)
  - United Nations (Box 94, Folder 1356)
  - United Nations of Pittsburgh (Box 94, Folder 1357)
  - UNICEF (United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund (Box 94, Folder 1358)
  - U.S.A. Magazine of American Affairs (Box 94, Folder 1359)
  - U.S. Public Health Service, 1959 (Box 94, Folder 1360)
  - U.S. Public Health Service, 1955-1958 (Box 95, Folder 1361)
  - U.S. Public Health Service Commissioned Officers Medical Care Service, 1956-1961 (Box 95, Folder 1362)
  - U.S. Public Health Service Commissioned Officers Medical Care Service, 1950-1955 (Box 95, Folder 1363)
  - U.S. Public Health Service. Communicable Disease Center, Atlanta. (Box 95, Folder 1364)
  - U.S. Public Health Service, 1951-1954 (Box 95, Folder 1365)
  - U.S. Public Health Service, 1949-1950 (Box 95, Folder 1366)
  - U.S. Public Health Service, 1948 (Box 95, Folder 1367)
  - U.S. Public Health Service, Report of Study Group on Mission and Organization of the PHS (Box 95, Folder 1368)
  - U.S. Public Health Service, Retired Officers' Steering Committee on Recruitment (Box 95, Folder 1369)
  - University Club, The (Pittsburgh) (Box 95, Folder 1370)
  - V - Miscellaneous (Box 95, Folder 1371)
  - Virology Conference. Gustav Stern Symposium (Box 95, Folder 1372)
  - W - Miscellaneous (Box 96, Folder 1373)
  - X-Y-Z - Miscellaneous (Box 96, Folder 1374)
- Talks, Papers, XX.
  - Good Health is Good Business. Industrial Hygiene Foundation, Nov. 18, 1948 (Box 96, Folder 1375)
  - Arthritis Rheumatism Foundation, December 6, 1948 (Box 96, Folder 1376)
  - Talk before Bankers Club, February 3, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1377)
  - The Frontiers of Medicine. Allegheny County Medical Society, Feb. 15, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1378)
  - The Road Ahead. Women's Auxiliary, Allegheny County Medical Society, March 22, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1379)
  - Medicine's Responsibility for the Coming Generation. American Academy of Pediatrics, April 2, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1380)
  - Talk before Twentieth Century Club, Pittsburgh, April 7, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1381)
  - Improving Public Health Through Professional Training. Pennsylvania Tuberculosis Society, May 26, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1382)
  - Industrial Health. N.Y. State Health Conference, June 22, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1383)
  - Medical Sciences and Education in Hospitals Today. Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of N.Y., Sept. 20, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1384)
  - The Future of the Hospital in Public Health. "Mercy Day", Mercy Hospital, September 22, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1385)
  - Thirteen Citizens' Committees William Penn Hotel, October 18, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1386)
  - Dinner honoring Elizabeth Fox, V.N.A., New Haven, Conn., October 19, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1387)
  - Westmoreland Public Health Association, November 3, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1388)
  - Pittsburgh and Its Medical Center, talk before Major Individual Gifts Comm., Building Fund Campaign, William Penn, November 18, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1389)
  - Radio script for VD Education Campaign Transcribed - KDKA, November 23, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 1390)
  - Colleges Schools of Pharmacy. Pharmacy and the Public Health Over, February 13, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1391)
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, Carnegie Music Hall, January 16, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1392)
  - Newman Club breakfast, St. Paul's, February 26, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1393)
  - Pittsburgh and Medical Leadership, Junior Chamber of Commerce, March 3, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1394)
  - Discussion at regional meeting of American College of Surgeons, Pittsburgh, March 14, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1395)
  - Public Health in the University of Pittsburgh. Pittsburgh Sec. American Chemical Society, March 23, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1396)
  - The School of Public Health and the Community, Allegheny branch, American Bacteriologists, March 25, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1397)
  - The Citizen's Stake In Public Health, Maritus Club, Ingomar, April 19, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1398)
  - Training For Public Health Action. Ohio Public Health Assn, Columbus, May 12, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1399)
  - Manuscript, Pittsburgh Medical Bulletin, Fall 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1400)
  - Peaks of Progress - Breakfasts Kaufmann's, June 1, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1401)
  - Bedford Community Hospital, September 19, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1402)
  - Symposium on Orthopedic Appliances. (Mellon Institute), September 22, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 1403)
  - The Purpose of Public Health Training First Seminar, and The Doctor of the Future, October 3, 1950 (Box 97, Folder 1404)
  - Women's Assn Univ. of Pittsburgh, October 4, 1950 (Box 97, Folder 1405)
  - Student Medical Society, talk., November 8, 1950 (Box 97, Folder 1406)
  - Health Landmark In Pennsylvania - talk Pennsylvania Bar Association, January 19, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 1407)
  - Conference on P.H. sponsored by W. Va. University Morgantown, W. Va., April 1, 1950 (Box 97, Folder 1408)
  - Visiting Nurse Association, Schenley Hall, Pittsburgh, Talk, April 10, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 1409)
  - Education and Research Programs of the School of Public Health, Talk - VA Hospital, Aspinwall, June 19, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 1410)
  - Status Prospects In Venereal Disease Control. Seminar on Venereal Disease, Harrisburg, April 27, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 1411)
  - Cleanliness Public Health, talk. Research Bureau for Retail Training, Univ. of Pittsburgh (University Club), June 20, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 1412)
  - Allegheny County Tuberculosis Secretaries Arsenal Health Center, Sept. 10, 1951, 10:30 a.m. (Box 97, Folder 1413)
  - Introductory remarks for Section III National Conference on Retirement of Older Workers} Arden House, Jan. 24-26, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 1414)
  - Health and Human Engineering, Centennial of Engineering, Chicago., Sept. 11, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 1415)
  - A Career In Public Health. Pub. in PHR Vol. 67, No. 10. P. 930-943, October, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 1416)
  - Pennsylvania's Health, Article for The Pennsylvania Clubwoman, Pennsylvania Federation of Women's Clubs, sent, 1-15-53 (Box 97, Folder 1417)
  - A Time For Decision. 50th anniversary, Henry Phipps Institute, Univ. of Pennsylvania, February 6, 1953 (Box 97, Folder 1418)
  - Over Population, Lecture at Cornell, April 30, 1953 (Box 97, Folder 1419)
  - Polio Lecture at Cornell, April 29, 1953 (Box 97, Folder 1420)
  - British Journal of Prev. Soc. Medicine Article by T. Parran and L. Falk (Box 97, Folder 1421)
  - Cancer, Lecture at Cornell, April 27, 1953 (Box 98, Folder 1422)
  - Science And Public Health, Mt. Mercy College, Catholic Round Table of Science, April 26, 1952 (Box 98, Folder 1423)
  - A Manual Of Corporate Giving, Chapter eleven - PUBLIC HEALTH (Box 98, Folder 1424)
  - The Doctor Of The Future, Mary Scott Newbolk lecture, college of Physicians of Philadelphia, November 5, 1952 (Box 98, Folder 1425)
  - A Basic Philosophy of Public Health, Middle Atlantic Hospital Assembly, Atlantic City, May 21, 1953 (Box 98, Folder 1426)
  - Collective Bargaining For Medical Care Benefits: A Recent Development in the USA, Parran Falk, Journal Prev. Soc. Med. V. 7, No. 3, p 87-93, July, 1953 (Box 98, Folder 1427)
  - Still Needed - Leadership, Georgetown Alumni dinner, at PAA, Nov. 7, 1953 (Box 98, Folder 1428)
  - Medicine in Maryland, Maryland Historical Soc., Baltimore Maryland Club, Nov. 16, 1953 (Box 98, Folder 1429)
  - The Impact of the Metropolis on the Professions, discussion Columbia Univ. Bicentennial, January 9, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 1430)
  - Allegheny County Boroughs Association annual dinner, William Penn Hotel, Pittsburgh, Jan. 25, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 1431)
  - Health Problems of Tomorrow University Catholic club, Foster Memorial, Pittsburgh, February 17, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 1432)
  - New Paths To A Growing Problem, Cutter Lectureship, Harvard School of P.H., May 6, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 1433)
  - Potentials Of The Catholic College, Mt. Mercy College Commencement, Pittsburgh, June 1, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 1434)
  - Pioneering For Health, Detroit Dental Society, February 2, 1955 (Box 99, Folder 1435)
  - The New Community Penn State Centennial, March 21, 1955 (Box 99, Folder 1436)
  - Tuberculosis - No Boundaries Respected. Pa. TB Health Society, William Penn, Pittsburgh, April 20, 1955 (Box 99, Folder 1437)
  - Harvard Medical School lecture, April 22, 1955 (Box 99, Folder 1438)
  - Health Around The World Alpha Omega Alpha, Syracuse University, April 28, 1955 (Box 99, Folder 1439)
  - Goals, Aims, Ambitions - GSPH Article for Allegheny County Medical Society Bulletin, September, 1955 (Box 99, Folder 1440)
  - Ergonomics and Public Health, Round Table on Human Engineering. Group sponsored by the ICA. (European Productivity Agency Project No. 33), Sept. 13, 1956 (Box 99, Folder 1441)
  - A Stronger Staff of Life, Penn State (Am. Assn. Of Agricultural Editors), July 18, 1956 (Box 99, Folder 1442)
  - National, Voluntary Health Agencies, discussion, American Philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 15, 1956 (Box 99, Folder 1443)
  - What Goes on In the School of Public Health, Common Industrial wastes, Dr. R. Hoak, 13 Dec, 1956 (Box 99, Folder 1444)
  - Closing The Gap (re: tuberculosis) State Committee on Tuberculosis Public Health, State Charities Aid Association, New York. 50th anniversary meeting, May 27, 1957 (Box 99, Folder 1445)
  - Health Care of Children in the U.S. and the U.S.S.R., Buffalo Children's Hospital, October 12, 1957 (Box 100, Folder 1446)
  - What Do You Mean By Public Health? Local Government Conference on Public Health (Institute of Local Government, Univ. of Pittsburgh), October 17, 1957 (Box 100, Folder 1447)
  - Hospitals In the Soviet Union, Hosp. Conf. Com., Hospital Council of Western Pennsylvania, October 25, 1957 (Box 100, Folder 1448)
  - Quadragesimo Anno, St. Paul's Cathedral Jubilee Celebration, Nov. 6, 1957 (Box 100, Folder 1449)
  - Medical Care in the Soviet Union, Medical Care Discussion Group, November 7, 1957 (Box 100, Folder 1450)
  - U.S. Naval Reserve Hospital Corps, Commissioning Ceremony, VA Hosp., Pittsburgh), Nov. 8, 1957 (Box 100, Folder 1451)
  - Uncle Sam, Why Are You Concerned, U.S. Public Health Service Water Pollution Control Administrators, Washington, February 20, 1958 (Box 100, Folder 1452)
  - Public Health Inside The USSR, APHA annual meeting, Cleveland, (NCC-WHO Forum Session - pub AJPH) v48 #5 May 1958 p.610-614, Nov. 13, 1957 (Box 100, Folder 1453)
  - "Public Health in the Space Age," California Medicine, 1958 (Box 100, Folder 1,453A)
  - World Health Assembly, re. Leon Bernard Award, acceptance speech, May 1958 (Box 100, Folder 1454)
  - "Help Needed!" American Journal of Public Health Editorial, February, 1958 (Box 100, Folder 1,454A)
  - Group Health Objectives, Group Health Assn. of America, Columbus, Ohio, 5/24/60 (Box 100, Folder 1455)
  - Duquesne University Commencement, June 5, 1960 (Box 100, Folder 1456)
  - Health Science in the Service of Man, Instituto Norteamericano de relaciones culturales, 1/28/61 (Box 100, Folder 1457)
  - The Profitable Enterprise, March 17-18, 1961 (Box 100, Folder 1458)
  - Helping at Home, National Council on Community Foundations, May 12, 1961 (Box 101, Folder 1459)
  - University of Pittsburgh Conference and commencement, June 9-10, 1961 (Box 101, Folder 1460)
  - Talks - Miscellaneous (Box 101, Folder 1461)
  - Quotations (Box 101, Folder 1462)
  - Reprints of speeches (Box 101, Folder 1463)
  - Requests for lectures, reprints, etc. (Box 101, Folder 1463-A)
- Lectures - Dr. Thomas Parran, XXI.
  - Cancer (Box 101, Folder 1464)
  - Cornell Lectures, 1965 (Box 101, Folder 1465)
  - Polio (Box 101, Folder 1466)
  - Population (Box 101, Folder 1467)
  - PH 203 - Seminar on Russia, Aug. 24, 1957 (Box 101, Folder 1468)
  - PHP 205 Dr. Parran's lecture notes, 1955-58 (Box 101, Folder 1469)
  - PHP 206 - Dr. Parran's lecture notes, 2/19/57 (Box 101, Folder 1470)
  - Disease lecture by Dr. Parran, 1956 (Box 101, Folder 1471)
  - International Health Lecture by Dr. Parran, 1957 (Box 102, Folder 1472)
  - The Profitable Enterprise, Symposium on World Medicine by Dr. Parran (Box 102, Folder 1473)
  - Internatioal Health Lecture, by Dr. Parran. Background materials (Box 102, Folder 1474)
- A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust, XXII.
  - Mellon, 1.
    - Re: Gift of Portrait of Dr. Parran to Univ. of Pgh., GSPH (Box 102, Folder 1475)
    - Letter of Gift re GSPH, Univ. of Pgh, 9/15/48 (Box 102, Folder 1476)